Hi, I'm Ginger Walker, owner of Clean Junkies.
We're going to talk today about how to wash your blue jeans, the proper way to wash your blue jeans.
When you're washing your blue jeans you want to make sure you're going to check your pockets, we're good on this one.
And you always turn your blue jeans inside out.
The reason for that is when you wash blue jeans, generally you're washing them together and the friction that the blue jeans have on each other wears the color down.
So if you turn them inside out you're not going to get as much of that.
Ah, sucker sticks, cell phones, keys and chap stick of course.
So it's very important to always check your pockets.
Turn your jeans inside out.
When you're washing blue jeans you don't want to wash more than four pair at a time and the reason why is, it's such heavy fabric that your washer, it can really wear on your washer.
But also again with the friction of jeans, that's going to wear down the denim and, and cause you to get holes easier and that type of things so stick with about four pairs of jeans.
Obviously if they're little jeans you can put a few more in there, but the heavier the material the more wear you're going to get on your washer.
Okay when we put in our blue jeans we're going to make, want to make sure that we put it on a heavy duty setting or you can use your normal setting.
The one thing that you want to pay attention to when you're doing your darks is your temperature.
You want to make sure that you're using cold water so that you can retain the color in your jeans.
If you've got a really dark jean you definitely want to use cold.
If you've got a lighter jean, an acid wash, something like that, you can use a warm setting but the best thing to do is always use cold, then you're set, you don't have to worry about it.
Okay, when your jeans are done washing, you'll get those out.
Now you can go ahead and throw your jeans in the dryer if you don't mind, you know, the color is going to fade eventually, or a lot of people will hang dry their jeans.
the best thing to do is turn them right side out again, give them a good shake, and hand them over something, you know, you can use as long as it doesn't, can't rust, you can use whatever you like.
So just give them a good hang there, let them air dry.
When they're done air drying, if you don't like that stiff feeling that the air drying will give you, you can throw them in the dryer for about ten minutes on a warm setting and it'll give you a nice soft feeling again.